<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[leroy's projects.]]></title><description><![CDATA[The description of this site]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 22:06:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Santa's Postal Service]]></title><description><![CDATA[The story Santa’s Postal Service is a seasonal store that sends beautifully crafted, authentic, Christmas letters from Santa Claus to…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/santas-postal-service/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/santas-postal-service/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;The story&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santa’s Postal Service is a seasonal store that sends beautifully crafted, authentic, Christmas letters from Santa Claus to children all over North America. This project started out as an MVP and through multiple rounds of iteration resulted in a conversion rate of 8.6% and over 2000 orders during the Christmas season. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santa’s Postal Service is a seasonal store, so naturally, the branding of the company will be jolly and festive, with lots of illustrations that match the theme of Christmas. The main focus of the store was authenticity ⁠— that we are actually Santa Claus from the North Pole, not the one sitting around in shopping malls. The idea of authenticity is critical. To create the feeling of realness, I manufactured the letterhead &amp;#x26; envelope using a linen paper stock, foil-stamped with silver &amp;#x26; gold, and wax-sealed using Santa’s signature S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Failed attempt #1 — Too complicated&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first version of Santa’s Postal Service was a failure. I assumed that customers wanted to customize their own Christmas letters — which cannot be further from the truth. People want a customized letter, but they do not want to spend the time to fully customize their own. In fact, only a 5% of customers chose to customize their own letters. Designing an experience around customizability resulted in unnecessary confusion and many Facebook comments about how difficult it was to create a letter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Attempt #2 — A Home Run!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After learning that people were confused about creating their Christmas Letters, I decided to develop an interface that focused on template selection instead of customizability. By prioritizing template selection, I came up with an elegant design that customers wanted to use and understood. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And nothing makes me happier than seeing happy customers posting about your product (:&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Panasonic]]></title><description><![CDATA[The story Having a little over a week to come up with a full-blown solution for the new micro-site, we approached this project different…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/panasonic/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/panasonic/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;The story&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a little over a week to come up with a full-blown solution for the new micro-site, we approached this project different than others by diving right into the deep end of building out a mock-up of the site first before research — an unorthodox approach which turned out in our best interest as we were able to maintain a constant feedback loop with the Panasonic team such that any necessary changes can be made early in the design phase of the iteration cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main challenge we faced during this build was creating a site that was fully internationalized to Chinese Canadians, which meant that the site had to be fully functional in English, Traditional Chinese, and Simplified Chinese with the design looking consistent across these languages. This was not an easy task to tackle as Chinese characters differ greatly to its English counterpart in typeface, letter spacing, and density. Something we learned early on during research was that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nngroup.com/articles/china-website-complexity/&quot;&gt;more than 90% Chinese web users surf the internet on their mobile phones and that they prefer high information density.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another challenge that we encountered was keeping a consistent styling between Chinese and English typography, as the boldness, styling, and spacing of the font tend to vary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, the best solutions to any difficult problem are the simplest ones, so that’s what we chose. Our simple solution was to create both a Chinese version of the microsite and an English version, both living on the same domain name but with the Chinese version in a subdirectory. Doing so provided us the flexibility to modify any changes of a site in one language without affecting the other. This proved valuable as it opened up the opportunity for us to use different images as well which helped increase focus to our target audience which in the end helped us achieve the campaign goal of selling out a whole inventory of luxury massage chairs all over Canada.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Holigos®]]></title><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/holigos/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/holigos/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dyson Supersonic]]></title><description><![CDATA[Approach Dyson reached out to us after noticing a similar project that we have built for Panasonic. In this project, we were an extension of…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/dyson/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/dyson/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Approach&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dyson reached out to us after noticing a similar project that we have built for Panasonic. In this project, we were an extension of Dyson’s existing design team and we first approached this project by studying their target audience and asking a multitude of questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What colours are present on Chinese New Year?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the Chinese audience use the internet differently?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How should we internationalize the site?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How should we present each feature in the most intuitive, engaging way?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These questions allowed us to determine our target audience and provides us a general idea of how the site will feel. As with most of our projects, we first start the project by drafting a mockup to visualize the structure of the different pages, image locations, and context of the copy. Doing so allows us and Dyson to align early on in the process to make quick changes and decide on what features are priorities in the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge of this build was creating a way to show how each attachment of the product functions together — there really were a lot of attachments, take a look below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking a look at the attachments alone, one would not be able to figure out how it works. Through a series of trial and errors coding different types of animations, we have concluded that the most elegant, simplistic solution is to present the attachment in a video format. Videos tend to improve user engagement when used sparingly which is a nice plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only downside of this solution is that videos take up bandwidths of the user’s data plan which is not ideal, especially so when more than 90% of Chinese users surf the web on their mobile phones. Nevertheless, we moved on with the solution by fully optimizing the speed of the site through techniques such as lazy-loading, lazy-sizing, and caching assets using a CDN. The results of the optimizations allowed us to gain excellent speed as determined by Google’s speed tool.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Local Bite]]></title><description><![CDATA[User Research & Rapid Prototyping The prototypes you see below were all designed and developed within a day. 4 prototypes were created in…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/localbite/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/localbite/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;User Research &amp;#x26; Rapid Prototyping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prototypes you see below were all designed and developed within a day. 4 prototypes were created in total and tested with users during 5 different a 1-hour study to validate any assumptions that were made. The learnings made from the 20 different studies were compiled to develop the first version of Local Bite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I researched the pain points of our local farmers, created a business case, and formulated a long-term strategy to achieve Local Bite’s long term goals and mission. Read More&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Sketch, I built a design system with components (called Symbols in Sketch) that behave and look consistent throughout the entire application. The design system includes colour palettes, typography, and various styles for different application states. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Illustrator, Photoshop, and Sketch, I created 4 prototype designs throughout the course of 1 month. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I tested 4 uniquely different interactive prototypes with specific groups of users and used InVision to map out the application flow. Each prototype was tested throughout 5 different 1-hour long interviews to answer specific questions, validate our assumptions, and gauge user interest. A total of 20 users were interviewed and the learnings were applied to our MVP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To test the interest level, I designed a landing page to see how many people would sign up for my Beta program email list. ($60 CAD in Facebook ads for 11 beta user signups). Visit landing page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed Local Bite’s landing page using Gatsby, a static site generator that is highly optimized for speed. Visit landing page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configured Webpack to bundle both server and client with support for SASS, CSS Modules, Typescript, Babel transpiler, hot module reloading, dev &amp;#x26; production environment builds, and prerendering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a React component library for inputs, buttons, modals…etc. Complex components were forked from Google’s Material-UI and other modules to shorten development time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed the front-end of the application with React&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and implemented a database using PostgreSQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed the back-end and implemented RESTful APIs, user verification &amp;#x26; authentication, password hashing, and error logging (for production).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated 3rd-party software for text, email, and image uploads (Twilio, Sendgrid, S3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Containerize the application using Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up the production environment: an NGINX reverse proxy running inside a container that points to the application port using Docker Compose; an SSL certificate is added to the domain name using Docker volumes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my interviews, I discovered that the best way to generate leads with the farming community is through phone or email. I hired 3 virtual assistants and we collected 1500 emails and Facebook pages that we would later contact regarding the launch of our app. Although we only reached out to 100 different farms, we earned 12 new users sign ups along with potential partnerships with various farmers’ markets. You can visit the application through the link below:&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Canam Systems]]></title><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/canam-systems/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/canam-systems/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Canam Sysz]]></title><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/canam-systems/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.app/canam-systems/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>